SONALI CHAPHEKAR

sonali_chaphekar@yahoo.com (510) 793 9112 (H) / (510) 396 1563(C)

SUMMARY:

Experience in IT includes, Support, Design, Development, Testing and Implementation of a variety of systems.

In-depth experience with Oracle 8i-10g, Developer 2000 (Forms 4.5/5.0/6.0/6.0i, Reports 2.5/3.0/6.0/6.0i), PL/SQL (Stored Procedures, Functions & Packages)

Very good understanding of Relational Database Design, Data Modeling and in-depth knowledge of Client Server Architecture.

Motivated, self-starter, excellent team player with good communication skills.

TECHNICAL PROFILE:

Hardware: HP-9000, SUN Sparc, Intel and AMD based HP and DELL Servers

Operating System: Linux, Solaris, HP-UX, MS Windows

Languages: SQL, PL/SQL, Python, JavaScript, XML, HTML, Java, Visual Basic,

VBScript, Shell Scripts.

RDBMs: Oracle 8i-10g, MS-Access, MySQL

GUI: Developer 2000 (Forms 4.5/5.0/6.0,6.0i, Reports 2.5/3.0/6.0,6i)

Applications: Oracle Financials Release 9.4.2, Oracle Assets 6.0.22

Tools/ Utilities: Export/Import, SQL*Loader, Explain Plan, TKPROF, TOAD, SQL

Navigator, SCCS, ClearCase, StarTeam

Testing Tools: Quality Center, Quick Test Pro (QTP) 8.2, Test Director,

WinRunner, LoadRunner

BI and Viz Tools : MS Office , Excel, Power BI, Tableau

Incident Management Software: Salesforce, BMC Remedy , JIRA

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE:

Quantros Inc. - Milpitas CA

Feb 2012 – Jan 2016

Roles: Senior Engineer Submissions /Support

Quantros was the premier provider of safety and quality solutions for healthcare organizations throughout the United States. Its web based Software-as-a-Service (SaaS) application helped over 2,000 healthcare facilities improve their care environment, resource productivity and financial performance.

Responsibilities:

- Handling regulatory submissions for agencies such as the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services (CMS), the Joint Commission (TJC) for many vendors.
- Responsible for data collection, formatting , analysis , processing and finally submitting data to CMS and TJC .
- Formatted and transformed customer raw data provided in XML , Excel and Flat files . Validated XML data file layout and contents .
- Involved in weekly support calls with clients.
- Provided email, phone and web support. Managed support related tickets in

- Salesforce and BMC remedy tool with given SLA and OLA.
- Responsible for analyzing complex client questions and discussing available features and limitations of the product with customers.
- Efficiently and timely resolved customer's technical requests.
- Wrote batch scripts on windows to automate common reporting tasks.
- Maintained support reports to track the number of cases created, case comments, case owners, case emails, case contact roles, cases with solutions, the length of time since the case last changed status and overall case history.
- Co-ordinated and assisted cross-functional team members development, QA, support, training, implementation, documentation with various activities such as product launch, training, support and documentation.
- Set up automated reports and dashboard in the Salesforce.
- Involved in Beta testing for ICD-10 migration for a handful of customers before the new features are rolled out to the market.
- Done in-house UAT testing to make sure that application can handle required tasks in real-world scenarios according to specifications. Created test cases and documented the results.
- Identified, logged and tracked defects using Rally. Details have been reported through Rally to the development team.
- Participated in triage meetings.
- Attended monthly webinars and user groups. Provided the updates on support related activities to incorporate the contents in monthly newsletters to all clients.

Environment: Oracle 9i, Java, XML

FuturePath LLC, San Jose CA

Jan2010 - Dec 2011

Roles: Software Engineer

Responsibilities:

- Worked on setting up the website for the company.
- Configured WordPress 2.8 with SQL Server & XML on Windows.
- Involved in the development of a website.
- Working as a web administrator.
- Responsible for maintaining and updating the contents and adding blogs.
- Used SqlLdr to load data from flat files to SQL tables.

Maxager Technology Inc, Redwood Shores CA

Jan 2006 - Dec 2008

Roles: Product Support Engineer

Worked on the company's web based ERP solution. This reporting tool is ideal for the manufactures with a wide range of products, customers and assets. Its profit-driven planning and performance management solution helps manufacturing companies to increase the cash and profit worth 3-5% of revenue. Application uses both margin and production velocity information to analyze historical data and generate realistic forward modeling that provides management teams an entirely new level of control over Return on Assets (ROA) rather than traditional margin only analysis. ROA is a key gauge/measure to evaluate a company's profitability in relation to its total Assets. Application calculates precisely how fast each product, customer, or market generates cash and profit from the assets. This allows managers to truly optimize product mix & customer mix profitability, sales & profit

planning, strategic pricing, and production planning.

- Historical report
- IP Interactive planning report what -if analysis
- Comparison report
- Trended comparison report
- Variance analysis unit based and minute based report.

Responsibilities:

- Responsible for doing and troubleshooting the monthly data loads on the production site.
- Automated data transformation and loads on production.
- Involved in writing Procedures, Functions, Triggers, Packages for existing systems.
- Worked on performance tuning for long running queries using explain plan, TKProf
- Wrote various batch scripts, SQL scripts and xml programs.
- Involved in doing various support activities like installations, weekly builds and backups.
- As a support person, I contributed to the quality assurance and manual software testing process. Logged bugs using JIRA and coordinated with the engineering team.
- Identified bugs and reported them through Bugzilla as well.
- Involved in fixing the bugs.

Environment: Oracle 9i. PL/SQL, SQL Navigator 3.0, Toad, Java, XML, Tomcat 6

ESTUATE INC. Mountain View, CA

Jul 2005 - Dec 2005

Roles: Quality Assurance Engineer

Responsibilities:

As a QA Developer

- Involved in design and development of test plan and test cases for the Oracle Accounts Payable Expense Reports module (Oracle Applications 11.5.9 & 11.5.10)
- Reviewed Business Requirement Documents and Technical Specifications.
- Created Test cases, identified various scenarios and tracked expected results in the Quality Center.
- Involved in testing of Web-application screens using the testing tool QuickTest Professional (QTP).
- Involved in GUI testing, Functional testing and Data Driven testing.
- Generated VB scripts in Expert View for different test cases and analyzed the test results.
- Involved in editing scripts and playing back the scripts and fixing the bugs.
- Attended weekly test plan/project status meetings and reviews.
- Participated in bug triage meetings periodically.
- Profound knowledge in SDLC and STLC with Test Design & Analysis, Test Strategy, Test case writing, Integration, Functional, Regression Testing, Test Data Management.
- Extensively used Quick test professional for functional testing in conjunction with Quality Center.
- Used Quality Center for defect logging, tracking, managing, and analyzing application defects.

- Worked with developers to resolve the issues by providing the detailed functionality.
- Involved in writing SQL scripts, and reports for quality center databases.

Environment: Oracle Payables 11.5.10

Tools: Quality Center, Quick Test Professional 8.2

Vircon Inc - Client - Wells Fargo Bank, San Francisco, CA Sept 2001 - Oct 2002

Roles: Software Development / Testing **Active Customer Management System**

Customers need to buy real estate, acquire a new business or franchise, purchase business equipment, or increase working capital. Dun & Bradstreet Corporation a global provider of credit reports gives credit and risk evaluation reports on Wells Fargo customers. Depending upon those reports the system evaluates whether it is a good customer or high-risk customer and grants loans accordingly. System also maintains the profiles of those customers and their loan information. Worked as a programmer with a business banking group on an active customer management system.

Responsibilities:

- Develop various monthly / quarterly statistical reports for financial analysts.
- Wrote interface to import data from Excel spreadsheet using SQL*Loader and PL/SQL
- Automated monthly reporting process using DBMS JOBS & batch files.
- Performance tuning for long running reports using explain plan and TKprof.

Environment: Oracle 8i, Forms 6i, Reports 2.5, PL/SQL 8, Windows NT

IpVerse System, Sunnyvale

Sep 2000- Mar 2001

Roles: Software Development / Testing

Responsibilities:

- Involved in the analysis, design and development of a software package for IpVerse. This system is designed to maintain information for Network elements, Routing elements and Subscriber services.
- Involved in data modeling. This involved normalization and denormalization (for performance) of data. Prepared ERDs and function hierarchy diagrams.
- Involved in development of various subprograms using PL/SQL. This includes writing numerous stored procedures, function and database triggers.
- Involved in development of various batch jobs using PL/SQL and Unix shell scripts.
- Involved in development of many interface programs, which loads, validates and updates data from comma-separated files. Used SQL*Loader, PL/SQL to load & validate data.
- Wrote numerous wrapper shell scripts to run different PL/SQL jobs using Unix corn utility and email job status for different distribution groups.
- Developed GUI interfaces using Forms 6.0, to maintain network elements.
- Involved in the development of standard template form and library to keep the standards through the development.
- Wrote numerous data validation functions & procedures, which follows the same business logic as Forms 6.0 front end. These procedures & functions were used by JAVA programmers for validation.

Environment: Oracle 8i, Forms 6i, Reports 6i, PLSQL

DELTAGEN, Menlo Park CA

May 2000- Sep 2000

Roles: Software Development

Histopathology System

The system maintains organizational data with organ details.

Responsibilities:

- Involved in analysis, development, testing and enhancement of biological information for Deltagen.
- Wrote interface programs using PL/SQL to export data from transaction tables into warehouse tables.
- Data Migration from Excel to Oracle. (Used SQL*Loader extensively)
- Developed various GUI screens using Oracle Forms 6i for maintaining the tissue information.
- Wrote database triggers and various subprograms for implementing complex business rules.
- Generated various reports using Report 2.5 as per the requirement.
- Interacted with users in development of the project.

Environment: Oracle 8i, Forms 6i, Reports 6i, PLSQL

GE CAPITAL CONTAINER FINANCE, San Francisco CA

Sep 1999 - Mar 2000

Roles: Fixed Assets System Maintenance & Reporting

Responsibilities:

- Ad-hoc reporting for existing fixed assets systems like reporting Net Book Value of assets, Depreciation reporting etc.
- Wrote many shell scripts to run different long running reports in batch mode.
- Wrote SQL*Loader / Unix shell scripts to upload mass asset information into foundation tables.
- Responsible for registering new reports / forms and processes in foundation.
- Responsible for regression testing and asset uploading.
- Wrote lots of PL/SQL batch scripts to extract attribute and segment information in much readable format, which is used by MS Access users for different business needs.
- Involved in enhancement of existing PL/SQL Packages for container handling systems.

Environment: HP-9000/891, Oracle 7.3, Developer 2000, Oracle Financials 9

MICHO (MOTOR INDUSTRIES CO.LTD), India

lun 1996 - lan 1998

Roles: Software Engineer

Inventory Control System - This system is developed to maintain the standard inventory control functions such as stock inquiry, last cost, average cost, suggested reorder quantities. It provides current information about what is in stock, on order, or committed on any given inventory item. The Inventory file is the focal point for all MRP (Material Requirements Planning) and purchasing activities. The system generates various reports like stock in hand, Inventory requirements forecasting, warehouse transfer tickets, and many other reports. Responsible for Development

Responsibilities

• Interacting with the client and understanding the business processes.

- Design of the operational flow, preparing design documents, Flow charts and Prototyping.
- Analyzing the data requirements of the system and designing the database objects.
- Developing the system using Forms 3.0 as the front-end tool. Providing a facility for the user to enter insurance information in the system. Incorporating validations so as to ensure accuracy of data.

Environment: Oracle 7.3, Forms 3.0, Report Writer, HP 9000

EDUCATION:

- MS Computer Science (University of Pune)
- BS Computer Science (University of Pune)
- Unix Administration Course DVC Concord, CA
- Java & C++ Course DVC Concord, CA